Lelah Bates Childs

Curious and creative problem-solver transitioning to a career in tech.

Strengths in frontend and backend development and experience with the MERN stack. I'm excited to leverage and grow my current skill set as part of a motivated team making the internet a better place.

Brooklyn, NY (612) 695-6190 labchilds@gmail.com labchild on GitHub

EXPERIENCE

Verblio, Remote — CONTRACT: Copy Editor and SEO Specialist

FEBRUARY 2021 - PRESENT

Contract position editing and optimizing blog posts and other content.

Gran Tivoli & Peppi's Cellar, New York, NY — *Bartender*

SEPTEMBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

Bartender in casual-fine dining restaurant and underground speakeasy.

The Cauldron Pub and Magical Experience, New York, NY — Assistant General Manager

APRIL 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019

FOH and BOH manager in a 2-story cocktail bar & gastropub.

City Winery, New York, NY — Bartender, Event Captain, Manager

NOVEMBER 2014 - APRIL 2019

FOH and BOH manager in multi-venue restaurant, concert, and event space beginning October 2018. Bartender in the wine bar, concert space, and captain during private events before October 2018.

The Hub Soho by Superchief Gallery, New York, NY — Ops and

Events Coordinator

SEPTEMBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

Managed social media pages and website; created and designed all hard-copy material for gallery shows and events, including wall text and catalogs; organized and executed openings and private events.

Lyssé, New York, NY — *E-commerce and Marketing Assistant*

NOVEMBER 2014 - APRIL 2019

Designed visual assets and wrote copy for the website, marketing materials, and ad buys; assisted at all photo shoots.

SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS, & JavaScript
- Browser-based libraries
 (Bootstrap & jQuery)
- Server-side development (MERN stack, PWAs)
- Databases (MySQL & MongoDB)
- ORM & ODM (Sequelize & Mongoose)
- API interaction (REST, JSON, AJAX, GraphQL)
- Unit testing
- Adobe Creative Suite (Illustrator, PhotoShop, InDesign)

EDUCATION

Columbia University,

New York, NY — *Certificate*

SEPTEMBER 2021 - MARCH 2022

Completed the Full Stack Engineering Bootcamp with 97% average.

Skidmore College,

Saratoga Springs, NY — Bachelor of Science

AUGUST 2010 - MAY 2014

Majored in Studio Art; double focus in Textiles and Painting, minor focus in Animation.